health.gov.au 2005-06-15

# Copyright Information

* * *

Copyright | Use of materials and information | Commercial and other use | Department of Health and Ageing enquiries | Linking to this site | Disclaimer | Quality of information - always check the information | Links to extrnal websites | Security of the Department of Health and Ageing's website | Access for people with a disability | Privacy statement | Security level | Clickstream data and cookies | Personal information | Queries, concerns and further information | Glossary  

## Copyright

Commonwealth government information and materials on this website, including data, pages, documents, online graphics, images and web pages, audio and video are protected by copyright, unless specifically notified to the contrary.

All Copyright Permission Requests should be forwarded to the Commonwealth Copyright Administration located at the Australian Government Attorney-General's Department.   
The contact details for the Commonwealth Copyright Administration are:

**Postal Address:**  
Commonwealth Copyright Administration  
Attorney-General's Department  
Robert Garran Offices  
National Circuit  
Canberra ACT 2600

**Website:** www.ag.gov.au/cca

### Use of materials and information

You may download, store in cache, display, print and copy a single copy or part of a single copy of information or material from this site only for your personal, non-commercial use and only in an unaltered form.

Information or material from this site may be used for the purposes of private study, research, criticism or review, as permitted under the Copyright Act 1968 and may only be reproduced as permitted under the Copyright Act 1968 (a copy of the Act is available at SCALEplus the legal information retrieval system owned by the Australian Attorney General's Department, at [http://scaleplus.law.gov.au](http://scaleplus.law.gov.au/)). 

Any permitted reproduction made must acknowledge the Commonwealth source of any selected passage, extract, diagram or other information or material reproduced. Any reproduction made of the information or material must include a copy of the original copyright and disclaimer notices as set out here. 

### Commercial and other use

You are not permitted to re-transmit, distribute or commercialise the information or material without seeking prior written approval from the Commonwealth. For written permission to use the information or material from this site, please contact the Department of Health and Ageing enquiries. You may not use this website to sell a product or service, or to increase traffic to your website for commercial reasons, such as advertising sales. 

* * *

## Department of Health and Ageing enquiries

Please email the webmaster with any questions you may have about our programs or policies, or to provide feedback on this website. 

The contact information is: 

**Email:** [enquiries@health.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@health.gov.au)

**Postal:**  
MDP 62  
GPO Box 9848  
CANBERRA ACT 2601   

### Linking to this site

You may link to this site, but permission is restricted to making a link without any alteration of the site's contents. Permission is not granted to reproduce, frame or reformat the files, pages, images, information and materials from this site on any other site unless express written permission has been obtained from the webmaster at the Department of Health and Ageing.

The Department of Health and Ageing reserves the right to prevent linking by giving notice. 

* * *

## Disclaimer

### Provision of education and research information only - always seek professional advice

This website is presented by the Australian Government Department of Health and Ageing for the purpose of disseminating health information free of charge for the benefit of the public. This website is not a substitute for independent professional advice. Nothing contained in this site is intended to be used as medical advice and it is not intended to be used to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease, nor should it be used for therapeutic purposes or as a substitute for your own health professional's advice. The Australian Government Department of Health and Ageing does not accept any liability for any injury, loss or damage incurred by use of or reliance on the information.

### Quality of information - always check the information

The Australian Government Department of Health and Ageing makes every effort to ensure the quality of the information available on this website and updates the information regularly. Before relying on the information on this site, however, users should carefully evaluate its accuracy, currency, completeness and relevance for their purposes, and should obtain any appropriate professional advice relevant to their particular circumstances. The Australian Government Department of Health and Ageing can not guarantee and assumes no legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, currency or completeness of the information. 

### Links to external websites

This website contains links to other websites which are external to the Australian Government Department of Health and Ageing. The Australian Government Department of Health and Ageing takes reasonable care in selecting linking websites. It is the responsibility of the user to make their own decisions about the accuracy, currency, reliability and correctness of information contained in linked external websites. 

Linkage to external websites should not be taken to be an endorsement or a recommendation of any third party products or services offered by virtue of any information, material or content linked from or to this site. Users of links provided by this site are responsible for being aware of which organisation is hosting the site they visit. 

Views or recommendations provided in linked sites do not necessarily reflect those of the Commonwealth. 

### Security of the Department of Health and Ageing's website

Every endeavour is made to ensure that this site is secure. However, users should be aware that the World Wide Web is an insecure public network that gives rise to a potential risk that a user's transactions are being viewed, intercepted or modified by third parties or that files which the user downloads may contain computer viruses or other defects. 

The Commonwealth accepts no liability for any interference with or damage to a user's computer system, software or data occurring in connection with this website. Users are encouraged to take appropriate and adequate precautions to ensure that whatever is selected from this site is free of viruses or other contamination that may interfere with or damage the user's computer system, software or data. 

### Access for people with a disability

Material produced through the web is a service covered by the Disability Discrimination Act 1992 (DDA). This requirement applies to any individual or organisation developing a World Wide Web page or placing or maintaining a web page on an Australian server. The provision of this information through the internet is in itself a service and as such, is covered by the DDA. 

Top of page  

* * *

## Privacy statement

### Information collection and privacy protection

The Department of Health and Ageing makes every effort to adhere to the Guidelines for Federal and ACT Government World Wide Websites developed by the Australian Privacy Commissioner (available at <http://www.privacy.gov.au/internet/web/index.html>). In particular we make every effort to comply with Information Privacy Principles (see Glossary below) 1 to 3 and 10 and 11 of the Privacy Act 1988 (a copy of the Act is available at SCALEplus the legal information retrieval system owned by the Australian Attorney General's Department at [http://scaleplus.law.gov.au](http://scaleplus.law.gov.au/)). 

This page explains the type of information that is collected by the Department of Health and Ageing, how such information is used and under what circumstances and to whom it may be disclosed. If you have any privacy concerns, you should direct them to the [webmaster](mailto:enquiries@health.gov.au). 

### Your email address

The Department of Health and Ageing will only record your email address in the event that you send us a message by email or if you register requesting notifications. Registration for notifications may be made initially by email, postal mail or facsimile. Your email address will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it and will not be added to any mailing lists without your prior consent by way of a specific request in writing. We will not use or disclose your email address for any other purpose, without your prior written consent. 

### Security level

The Department of Health and Ageing website has been tested to an advanced level of site security. 

### Clickstream data and cookies

Department of Health and Ageing uses a 'cookie' for maintaining contact with a user through a website session. A cookie is a small file supplied by Department of Health and Ageing and stored by the web browser software on your computer when you access Department of Health and Ageing site. (An explanation of cookies generally can be found at the site of the Australian Privacy Commissioner). The cookie allows the Department of Health and Ageing to recognise you as an individual as you move from one page to another. 

This cookie will be immediately lost when you end your internet session and shut down your computer. Our copy of your information will be automatically deleted twenty minutes after you last used the system. This information is only used to help you use our website systems more efficiently, not to track your movements through the internet, or to record private information about you. 

Any system on this website that records information about you will specifically ask your permission first. 

The Department of Health and Ageing makes a record of your visit and logs the following information for statistical purposes: 

* the user's server address 
* the user's top level domain name 
* the date and time of access to the site 
* pages accessed and documents downloaded 
* the previous site visited 

This information is analysed to show broken links in our website, bottlenecks, and other site problems. We use this information to redesign for efficiency of use. 

No attempt will be made to identify anonymous users or their browsing activities unless legally compelled to do so, such as in the event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect the Internet Service Provider's log files. 

### Personal information

Information provided through the Department of Health and Ageing website will comply with Information Privacy Principles (see Glossary below), and particularly principles 1 to 3 and 10 and 11. Stated simply these principles are 

**Principle 1** \- Collection of information must be lawful and fair  
**Principle 2** \- Informing people why information is collected  
**Principle 3** \- Ensuring personal information collected is of good quality and not too intrusive  
**Principle 10** \- Limiting the use of personal information to the purposes for which it was collected  
**Principle 11** \- Preventing the disclosure of personal information outside the agency.

(wording on simplified principles supplied to dept. by the Office of Federal Privacy Commissioner)

### Queries, concerns and further information

If you have any queries, concerns or require further information relating to privacy and Department of Health and Ageing, you are invited to email the Department. 

Top of page  

* * *

### Glossary

**Domain name**  
The code for the country or type of internet connection a user comes from, such as '.com' '.gov' '.au' '.uk' 

**Information Privacy Principles**  
11 principles established under section 14 of the Privacy Act 1988. Commonwealth and ACT government agencies must comply with these principles in their handling of personal information in their possession. The principles can be accessed at SCALEplus, the legal information retrieval system owned by the Australian Attorney General's Department (at [http://scaleplus.law.gov.au](http://scaleplus.law.gov.au/)). 

**Internet Service Provider**  
A company or organisation that provides access to the internet for users. 

**Law enforcement agency**  
An agency of the Commonwealth or a State or Territory such as the Australian Federal police, which exercises powers such as executing a warrant to seize documentation or goods or to search premises etc 

**Notification**  
Automatic advice of new or updated material available via the Department of Health and Ageing, provided to a user who registers for this service. 

Top of page  

**Page currency, Latest update: 06 June, 2005**
